A Guide to the Papers of Armistead Page Booker, 1943-1990
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Papers of Armistead Page Booker 1943-1990
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-32
1 box, 5" x 10.5"
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Sally Cary Booker, the daughter of Armistead Page Booker, donated the material in 2002.
Biographical Information
Armistead Page Booker graduated from the University of Virginia School of Medicine in 1943. He was an Intern on Medicine at UVa in 1943 and completed two years as an Assistant Resident and Resident on Pediatrics in 1947. Following his residency he became a Clinical Instructor in Pediatrics at the University of Virginia, a position he held until he became a Clinical Assistant Professor in Pediatrics in the 1965-66 school year. Named an Associate Professor in 1973-74, he served in this capacity until 1984-85. Dr. Booker was active in the Albemarle County Medical Society and was Secretary-Treasurer in 1952 and 1953, Vice-President in 1967, and President in 1968.
Scope and Content
The collection includes diplomas earned by Booker, several photographs, and two drafts of papers giving a brief history of the Albemarle County Medical Society with information about various Charlottesville physicians and medical institutions, and a manuscript about Dr. Lawrence Thomas Royster.
Arrangement
The material is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Armistead Page Booker diploma 1943 December 31, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01-001)
  Diploma awarded by UVa Hospital for Intern on Medicine.
- Armistead Page Booker diploma 1949 June 30, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01-002)
  Diploma awarded by UVa Hospital for Assistant Resident and Resident on Pediatrics.
- Armistead Page Booker diploma 1953 October 1, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01-003)
  Diploma awarded by Virginia Pediatric Society.
- Armistead Page Booker diploma 1965 September 17, 1 diploma (Box-folder 01-004)
  Diploma awarded by UVa School of Medicine for being a charter member of the Advisory Committee.
- Department of Pediatrics, University of Virginia 1977, June 2, 1 B&W 8 x 10 photo (Box-folder 01-005)
- "The Albemarle County Medical Society: A History from the Department of Pediatrics..." by Armistead P. Booker 1982 August, 1 AM, 13 pp.; 1 B&W 8 x 10 photo; 1 TN, 1 p. (Box-folder 01-006)
- Department of Pediatrics memo 1982 October 22, 1 memo, 2 pp. (Box-folder 01-007)
  Memo regards proposed changes for Medical Center medical records.
- "A History of the Albemarle County Medical Society" by Armistead P. Booker, From: Department of Pediatrics 1982 November, 1 TM with AN, 64 pp.; 2 photocopied journal excerpts; 1 AN, 2 pp. (Box-folder 01-008)
  The history includes information about the UVa Infirmary, Charlottesville General Hospital, Piedmont Hospital, the University Dispensary, the Martha Jefferson Sanatorium and Hospital, University of Virginia Hospital, Blue Ridge Sanatorium, the Health Department, the Children's Rehabilitation Center, a list of Albemarle County physicians for the year 1850, and a description of the Experimental Medical Care Review Organizaion (EMCRO). Booker writes about a number of prominent physicians, including, James Lawrence Cabell, John Staige Davis (1824-85), James Edgar Chancellor, Robert William Nelson, William Beverly Towles, William Cecil Dabney, Paul Brandon Barringer, John Staige Davis (1866-1933), Harvey Earnest Jordan, Hugh Thomas Nelson, Edward May Magruder, Halstead Shipman Hedges, Thomas Henry Daniel, Stephen Hurt Watts, William Hall Goodwin, James Carroll Flippin, Staige Davis Blackford, Byrd Stuart Leavell, Henry Bearden Mulholland, Vincent William Archer, James Robert Cash, David Cole Wilson, McLemore Birdsong, and Wilmer Howard Paine.
- Department of Pediatrics memo and minutes 1982 December 17, 1 memo, 1 p.; 1 TD, 3pp. (Box-folder 01-009)
- Division of Pediatric Infectious Diseases 1982?, 1 TD, 9 pp. (Box-folder 01-010)
  Members and research interests.
- "Midway building housed schools, hotel, Confederate hospital in past." The Observer, July 19-25 and "A Brief History of Historic First Baptist Church on Its Anniversary." Charlottesville-Albemarle Tribune, December 8, 1988. 1988, [1990], 2 newspaper clippings (Box-folder 01-011)
- Lawrence Thomas Royster, M.D., 1874-1953 N.D., 1 AM, 16 pp. (Box-folder 01-012)